<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FLL Tutorials</title>
    <description>A one stop shop for everything FIRST LEGO League</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 14:32:35 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 14:32:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.7</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Educator++</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This base robot can be built with the core education kit with a few extra parts (additional color sensor and two liftarms).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design by Einav Bar-Nir, D-Bug FRC 3316&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design Files:
 &lt;a href=&quot;/en/RobotGame/Educator%2B%2BEnglish.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF English&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/en/RobotGame/Educator++.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF עִברִית&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/robotgame/building/one%20kit%20build/2020/07/06/Educator++.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/robotgame/building/one%20kit%20build/2020/07/06/Educator++.html</guid>
        
        <category>RobotDesigns</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>RobotGame</category>
        
        <category>Building</category>
        
        <category>One Kit Build</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minecraft Server</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity: Minecraft Server&lt;br /&gt;
Author: Sanjay from FRC 8027
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team bonding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each student will need a copy of the same edition of Minecraft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up your own multiplayer, private Minecraft server. Follow instructions below:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/download/server/&quot;&gt; Java Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/download/server/bedrock/?fbclid=IwAR0HLjchnLOuu3gt3Fx8jNaKWxo_DEaX33-HwAr04-rq6--MBczZyFHMEos&quot;&gt; Bedrock Edition &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the server to play with each other. One student will have to host and setup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noip.com/support/knowledgebase/general-port-forwarding-guide/&quot;&gt;port forwarding&lt;/a&gt; on his or her router so that the rest of the team can access the server. You can talk to each other over Zoom or Discord to chat at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notes:&lt;/b&gt;
Minecraft is a popular block building game. There are many publicly available Minecraft servers. Some are moderated and others are not. For a FIRST LEGO League team, we recommend that you set up a private one yourself so that your team and your invited guests know it will be a safe environment. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/how-to-make-minecraft-server/&quot;&gt; Article on Minecraft servers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/18/Minecraft.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/18/Minecraft.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deserted Island</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity: Deserted Island&lt;br /&gt;
Author: Alex from FRC 8027
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The activity will help with quick decision making and strategic planning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is nothing needed but you could use a picture of an island to get an idea of resources available and the location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional: Screen share a picture of an island to give the team the basis of what they are doing and their objective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are stranded on a tropical deserted Island. The team must first think of the three items that they are going to start with, then using the items and whatever is determined as the natural resources, the team must come up with a way to survive on the island, and eventually escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notes:&lt;/b&gt;
Everyone must participate. The scenario is to be kept as realistic as possible. For example, there is no phone service or wifi on the island.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/11/Deserted-Island.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/11/Deserted-Island.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Acts of Kindness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity: Acts of Kindness&lt;br /&gt;
Author: Lucas from FRC 8027
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team will learn what fellow members appreciate about them. This will help them gain a more personal connection with fellow teammates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The coach should randomly pair up students on the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide each student the contact information for their match (email, text, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each pair will let their partner know what they appreciate the most about them. They can email the message or send a text, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notes:&lt;/b&gt;
This activity can be completed even if there are new students on the team. If a pair of students have never interacted before, they can instead write about what they would like to know about their partner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/10/Acts-of-Kindness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/10/Acts-of-Kindness.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity: Best Sell&lt;br /&gt;
Author: Eli from FRC 8027
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The goal of this activity is to learn to present your ideas to others quickly and effectively. Students will have a chance to be creative. Students will also learn how to appropriately share feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All that is needed is a way for each student to write down their ideas and a way for the students to vote on an idea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is for the team to come up with the best idea and pitch to try to sell their product.
Each team member should pick a product or idea.
Create a short, yet effective pitch in 5mins for this product or idea.
Pitch the idea to the team. Listen to the feedback from the rest of the team.
After all the pitches are given everyone votes, for whatever they think was the best idea and the best pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notes:&lt;/b&gt;
 This activity can also be done in teams. Another variation is for each student to come up with a wacky invention idea, but has to trade with someone else on the team. This way, they will be creating a pitch for another student’s idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/09/Best-Sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/09/Best-Sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guess What</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity: Guess What
Author: Ben from FRC 8027
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Through this activity teams will learn how to work efficiently and use teamwork to solve a problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Different images that the team will have to describe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Coach needs to have a set of images or objects ready ahead of time. He/she can screen-share the images or hold up photographs/object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The activity begins with the oldest team member with a blind fold. The coach will share the image/object with the rest of the team. The rest of the team needs to pick no more than five words to describe the object. You may not name the object itself. The student who is blindfolded must guess what object is being held up within a minute and a half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notes:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/08/Guess-What.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/08/Guess-What.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two Truths One Lie</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity: Two Truths One Lie&lt;br /&gt;
Author: Ramsey from FRC 8027
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;
The objective of this game is to get to know personal information about the other call members by saying three statements one of which is true. The first person to guess correctly gets a point.The first person to get 3 points wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Note cards or a shared document online with truths and lies for each student listed on them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each member of the call has around 3-5 groups of truths and lies assigned to them before the game starts by the coach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting from oldest to youngest, the members on the call read the three statements for their assigned person. The other members of the call then have to guess which statement is false. Whoever guesses correctly first gets a point. The first to 3 points wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notes:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members of the call can split into teams, depending on the number of players you can have anywhere from 2 to 4 teams. Each team selects one member from their team to read their statements and it’s up to the other teams to guess which statement is wrong. If a member of your team guesses correct you get a point. The first team to score 5 points wins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/06/Truths-Lies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/06/Truths-Lies.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Online Pictionary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity:  Online Pictionary&lt;br /&gt;
Author: Ananth from FRC 8027
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;
This team building exercise is good for communication practice amongst team members and can increase their productivity while working in a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A small (or medium) sized whiteboard that you can draw the drawings on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or a piece of paper with a camera pointing straight down so others can see the drawing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or an paint program&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some markers/a pencil (if you are using paper) to draw the drawings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each member of the team should get their whiteboard and markers ready before the call and keep it near them while other people draw, so that they can be prepared for when he/she is the one to draw. Alternatively, the player can also use a paint program and share their screen. There are several free online paint programs (https://www.youidraw.com/apps/painter/).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team coach should come up with a list of words that he/she provides in a private chat to the person who is drawing. You can use a tool use as Pictionary Generator (https://randomwordgenerator.com/pictionary.php) if you need help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team members will be separated into two smaller groups and one person from either group will be chosen to draw a picture on the whiteboard and the members of that person’s smaller group have to attempt to guess what image he/she is drawing. If the group successfully guesses the drawing, they get a point, if they are unsuccessful, the other team has an opportunity to guess and steal the point. After this is over you will switch the drawer to a person from the other group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notes:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To increase the difficulty, you could have the drawer be on mute the entire time when he/she is constructing his/her drawing to prevent them from accidentally (or purposefully) revealing any information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, instead of separating into two smaller groups, you can stay in one larger group and try to get a high score and beat a personal goal (not competing against any other team).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/04/Online-Pictionary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/04/Online-Pictionary.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Online Multiplayer Jigsaw Puzzle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity:  Online Multi-player Jigsaw Puzzle&lt;br /&gt;
Author: Ananth from FRC 8027
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;
The team will learn to become more coordinated and will be given a chance to work together remotely on a task that requires focus and collaboration when in a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;
You will need to access the online puzzles located at http://www.epuzzle.info/multiplayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select “Create a Table” to start your own puzzle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a Private Puzzle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the link is generated, send that link to the rest of your team members so they can join that game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work together to solve the online puzzle with your team. Coordinate so that you solve the puzzle in the least amount of moves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notes:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/02/Online-Puzzle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/06/02/Online-Puzzle.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Photo Sharing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity:  Photo Sharing&lt;br /&gt;
Author: Arvind from FRC 8027
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn more about each other&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn what is important to each of us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each student on the team brings one photo that is meaningful to the student in some way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take turns presenting. Share why you picked that photo and what it represents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notes:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/05/31/Photo-Share.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/05/31/Photo-Share.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
