<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FLL Tutorials</title>
    <description>A one stop shop for everything FIRST LEGO League</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 12:59:42 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 12:59:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.7</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Supporting students of all Abilities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;FIRST LEGO League prides itself on being an inclusive program. A lot of coaches are nervous about how their students will be perceived by judges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following discussion has ideas posted on the Facebook Group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/FLLShareandLearn/&quot;&gt;FLL: Share &amp;amp; Learn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;will-my-team-get-penalized-if-a-student-with-disabilities-does-not-answer&quot;&gt;Will my team get penalized if a student with disabilities does not answer?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The most wonderful thing about FIRST is their inclusion. Each team member should be able to participate where their at and never be put on the spot to answer a question if they are not comfortable or able to answer. Please be sure to let your tournament directors know so they can let the judges know. We train our judges to not ask questions to specific students or mark teams down because everyone is not speaking or looking at judges. Meet students where they are at not where you think they should be is our motto here.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I have had quite a few students with moderate to severe speech issues. I usually let the judges know ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let the organizers know as soon as possible. I don’t know what region you are in, but I can tell you in my region they were awesome and would have bent over backwards to make sure your kids got the same opportunity others did. I’m sure other regions would be the same. As we used to tell our kids leading up to competition, every adult in that building wants them to succeed as much as they do, and they will do everything they can to make sure they shine at their moment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-can-i-accommodate-students-with-various-disabilities-on-the-team&quot;&gt;How can I accommodate students with various disabilities on the team?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you have a kid who won’t speak, make sure the judges know that, and give that kid a big role doing something non-speaking. (Otherwise, that kid is likely to get CALLED ON. If you have a kid who speaks comfortably and cues well, consider a plan for what if someone locks up, where a team member jumps in: “Johnny is has some challenges speaking in public, but he wrote/dictated the text for this/wrote this part of the code/etc.”)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask parents privately how to accommodate each of these kids. They have school plans describing accommodations that make them each successful and you can include these accommodations too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s going to be hard for judges to evaluate a presentation they can’t understand, so start thinking about how to ameliorate the challenges. Consider printing the script (in BIG fonts) on a big poster board (or flip chart) for any team member who is going to be hard to understand. This might be a team that needs a multiple-poster strategy, where ALL the content is on posters, and kids bring them up to the judges to show them one at a time. Make it big and legible, and if some of the talking isn’t intelligible, the ‘hit’ is going to be a lot smaller than if you’re relying on verbal delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whom-should-i-inform-if-i-have-a-student-with-a-disability-on-the-team&quot;&gt;Whom should I inform if I have a student with a disability on the team?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Please let your tournament director or judge advisor (or both!) know. I encourage our tournament director to include language in the emails we send to teams before the event to let us know about any accommodations that are needed. There is really very little official FIRST training for FLL judges now, so please don’t assume the judges will recognize neurodiverse kids.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Judge Adviser here…Let your tournament director know about your team. Judges are usually friendly people who try to make the experience a positive experience for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My son has PANDAS and Tourette’s and has been on a team for 4 seasons. We tell the judges ahead of time. He still participates in the skit but will try to keep his speaking parts smaller. This year is probably his last year and he’s a team captain, and had way more input into the robot, so it will be interesting. His Tourette’s is also worse than ever. But they need to learn to keep going through it, so it’s been great for teaching that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We also had a team of 9 neurodiverse kids last year. We went in assuming the judges would be able to tell, and that backfired on us in round 2. So I would just tell them. Kids are unpredictable, and nervous neurodiverse kids are even more so. Warm them ahead so they can have a heads up if there is unusual behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-am-worried-about-student-confidentiality-if-i-have-to-inform-judges&quot;&gt;I am worried about student confidentiality if I have to inform judges&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regarding confidentiality, that is something we take seriously. I specifically tell coaches not to provide any names and that we don’t need a detailed diagnosis, just a general note. I really like the suggestion of having teammates help lead the conversation. Teams that are able to do that seamlessly are noticed as it’s an awesome display of Core Values. The other thing I suggest is practice. Practice speaking in front of each other, invite parents/teachers to a mock judging and have them ask questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-am-worried-that-a-30-minute-judging-session-will-be-overwhelming-for-my-students&quot;&gt;I am worried that a 30-minute judging session will be overwhelming for my students.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When we switched to the 30 minute judging session there was a concern how kids with any sort of disability would handle it. Our region developed a process to accommodate this. I’ve heard feedback that it actually works better overall than the individual sessions as there is less quick change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/judging/competition%20day/2022/11/02/All-abilities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/judging/competition%20day/2022/11/02/All-abilities.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        <category>Judging</category>
        
        <category>Competition Day</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Useful Resources</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of useful resources for your season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also other alternative lists that might be helpful: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damienkee.com/lego-mindstorms-resources/&quot;&gt;Damien Kee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://stemrobotics.cs.pdx.edu/node/2837&quot;&gt; STEMRobotics&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legoengineering.com/online-training-courses/&quot;&gt;Lego Engineering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will update this guide as we find and review resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-lego-league-challenge-materials&quot;&gt;FIRST LEGO League Challenge Materials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.firstlegoleague.org/season#resources&quot;&gt;SUPERPOWEREDChallenge&lt;/a&gt;: Build Instructions, Robot Game Rulebook, and Updates&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://fllblog.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;FIRST LEGO League Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://firstinspiresst01.blob.core.windows.net/first-energize/fll-challenge/fll-challenge-superpowered-rubrics.pdf&quot;&gt;SUPERPOWERED Rubrics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://firstinspiresst01.blob.core.windows.net/first-energize/fll-challenge/fll-challenge-superpowered-judging-session-flowchart.pdf&quot;&gt;SUPERPOWERED Judging Flowchart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-curriculum-by-lego-education&quot;&gt;Free Curriculum by LEGO Education&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the built-in lessons in the EV3 Programming Software and the SPIKE Prime software that you installed on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-free-curriculum&quot;&gt;Other Free Curriculum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.education.rec.ri.cmu.edu/content/lego/ev3/&quot;&gt;CMU Robotics Academy &lt;/a&gt;: Complete introductory curriculum for the EV3&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stemcentric.com/ev3-tutorial&quot;&gt;STEMCentric&lt;/a&gt;: Mostly introductory-level with a few intermediate-level topics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wafflesrobotics.com/fll/fll-resources/&quot;&gt;WAFFLES Community Robotics&lt;/a&gt;: Comprehensive block by block introduction to programming by a FIRST team in Canada. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://stemrobotics.cs.pdx.edu/node/2643&quot;&gt;STEMRobotics&lt;/a&gt;: Organized repository for educational materials and curriculum guides for MINDSTORMS instructors by Portland State University.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ev3lessons.com&quot;&gt;EV3Lessons.com&lt;/a&gt;: Complete curriculum from beginner to advanced created by a FIRST Team and the Champion’s Award Winners of World Festival. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.primelessons.org&quot;&gt;PrimeLessons.org&lt;/a&gt;: Complete curriculum from beginner to advanced created by a FIRST Team and the Champion’s Award Winners of World Festival. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;organization-and-planning-resources-for-fll-teams&quot;&gt;Organization and Planning Resources for FLL Teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flltutorials.com/en/Worksheets.html&quot;&gt;Engineering Notebook Worksheets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flltutorials.com/en/Worksheets.html&quot;&gt;Unofficial Guide to the Superpowered season&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lessons-specific-to-first-lego-league&quot;&gt;Lessons Specific to FIRST LEGO League&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flltutorials.com/CoreValues.html&quot;&gt;Core Value Activities and Lessons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flltutorials.com/en/RobotGame.html&quot;&gt;Robot Designs and Lessons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flltutorials.com/en/Project.html&quot;&gt;Innovation Project Lessons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://flltutorials.com/CoachCorner.html&quot;&gt;Coach’s Corner&lt;/a&gt;: Articles with tips from teams around the world&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;robotics-resources-for-scouts&quot;&gt;Robotics Resources for Scouts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scouting.org/filestore/Merit_Badge_ReqandRes/Robotics.pdf&quot;&gt;Robotics Merit Badge Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cs2n.org/activities/courses/robot-virtual-worlds-boy-scout-robotics-merit-badge&quot;&gt;Robot Virtual Worlds Boy Scout Robotics Merit Badge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mindstormsspike-related-forums-and-facebook-groups&quot;&gt;MINDSTORMS/SPIKE-Related Forums and Facebook Groups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/FLLShareandLearn/&quot;&gt;FLL Share and Learn Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://forums.usfirst.org/forumdisplay.php?24-FIRST-LEGO-League&quot;&gt;FIRST LEGO League Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://listserv.jmu.edu/cgi-bin/wa?A0=VADCFLL-L&quot;&gt;VA-DC FIRST LEGO League Listserv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/legomindstorms/&quot;&gt;LEGO MINDSTORMS Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/792689664442601&quot;&gt;SPIKE Prime Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stores-to-buy-additional-lego-or-mindstorms-parts&quot;&gt;Stores to buy additional LEGO or MINDSTORMS parts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lego.com&quot;&gt;LEGO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legoeducation.com&quot;&gt;LEGO Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.lego.com/en-US/Pick-a-Brick&quot;&gt;LEGO Pick A Brick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.Bricklink.com&quot;&gt;Bricklink&lt;/a&gt;: For purchasing specific parts and complete sets&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.Brickowl.com&quot;&gt;Brickowl&lt;/a&gt;: For purchasing specific parts and complete sets&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mindsensors.com&quot;&gt;Mindsensors&lt;/a&gt;: For non-LEGO branded sensors that are compatible with the EV3&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hitechnic.com&quot;&gt;HiTechnic&lt;/a&gt;: For non-LEGO branded sensors that are compatible with the EV3&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;technic-and-mindstorms-books&quot;&gt;TECHNIC and MINDSTORMS Books&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isogawa, Yoshihito. The LEGO MINDSTORMS EV3 Idea Book&lt;br /&gt;
Isogawa, Yoshihito. The LEGO MINDSTORMS Robot Inventor Idea Book&lt;br /&gt;
Isogawa, Yoshihito. The LEGO Technic Idea Book&lt;br /&gt;
Kmiec, Pawel. The Unofficial LEGO Technic Builder’s Guide&lt;br /&gt;
Valk, Laurens. The LEGO MINDSTORMS EV3 Discovery Book&lt;br /&gt;
Kee, Damien. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damienkee.com/classroom-activities-ev3/&quot;&gt;Classroom Activities for the Busy Teacher: EV3&lt;/a&gt;. Also includes worksheets and challenges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;challengesprojects-for-ideas-inspiration-and-outreach&quot;&gt;Challenges/Projects for Ideas, Inspiration, and Outreach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theNXTstep.com&quot;&gt;The NXT Step&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mindstorms.dreschallenges.com/&quot;&gt;Dr. E’s Challenges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drgraeme.org/EV3/EV3.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Graeme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nxtprograms.com&quot;&gt;NXT and EV3 Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onekitprojects.com&quot;&gt;MINDSTORMS Robot Inventor Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damienkee.com/&quot;&gt;Dr. Damien Kee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ev3dev.org/&quot;&gt;EV3Dev&lt;/a&gt;: Projects that take the EV3 to the next level&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;competitions-using-lego-robots&quot;&gt;Competitions Using LEGO Robots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.firstlegolegue.org&quot;&gt;FIRST LEGO League&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wroboto.org&quot;&gt;World Robot Olympiad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://junior.robocup.org/&quot;&gt;RoboCup Junior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;virtual-programming-tools&quot;&gt;Virtual Programming Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gears.aposteriori.com.sg/&quot;&gt;GearsBot - not SPIKE Prime software (free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cmu.edu/roboticsacademy/roboticscurriculum/index.html&quot;&gt;CMU Robotics Academy Virtual SPIKE Prime (not free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/getting%20started/resources/2022/11/01/Recommendation-List.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/getting%20started/resources/2022/11/01/Recommendation-List.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        <category>Getting Started</category>
        
        <category>Resources</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Innovation Project Presentation Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presenting your Innovation Project in front of judges is an important part of the process. Here are some tips to help your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stay under the 5-minute time limit including setup time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even if you pick a creative theme for your presentation, you still need to share the information needed to fill in the rubric. Do not get caught up in the creative format and forget to share all the amazing content you have.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The best presentations include everything required in the rubric within the 5-minute time limit. Do not wait for Q&amp;amp;A to share critical information. Teams often find it challenging to cut their presentation down to 5-minutes, but this is an important step.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you pick a creative theme, pick something that is common knowledge or something that could be easily understood no matter what your culture/background so that your judges do not have to work hard: Star Wars? Shark Tank? Little Red Riding Hood? Newscast?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Simple props and costumes can help viewers understand the skit and characters better and make it more engaging. You do not have to spend a lot of money. Get creative with the resources you have. Create name tags, use hats, or borrow some props.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Prototypes and visuals can help your judges understand the work and give them something to focus on. Most events do not let teams leave anything with judges. Therefore, make sure that you share these visuals with your judges during the presentation and Q&amp;amp;A. Also note that prototypes/diagrams are included in the rubric and can earn your team points.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure that everyone is involved in the presentation. If some students are not comfortable presenting, think about what roles they can play or how you can help them become more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Support your teammates and respectfully help them out if they forget their lines or make a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Memorize your lines and make eye contact with each other and the judges. Ideally, you will not memorize the exact wording, but the general information you want to communicate in your line. If you need some ways to remember your lines, Condense your lines into a bulleted list to help you remember. (Watch &amp;lt;a href=https://youtu.be/d812a7qG9Kw”&amp;gt;this video &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for tips on how to practice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Practice your presentation many times and practice Q&amp;amp;A. Ask coaches and parents to act as judges and ask you questions about your project. Make sure that everyone on the team understands the project and can answer questions. Questions can be made up using the rubrics.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Some regions may require/allow slides along with your presentation. Keep in mind that most regions do not provide computers/projectors/screens. If you do choose to use slides, make sure that they are kept uncluttered and readable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not be afraid to go up close to the judges. They cannot see poster boards, images or prototypes that are far away.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many teams keep a Research Project Journal. In this journal they record their ideas, interviews, background research and progress each week. You can show the judges this journal and even use it to answer questions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some sample presentations for your inspiration. While they are from prior seasons where the rubric may have been different, they give you some idea of the possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zi7LRI4IBJU&quot;&gt;Video 1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/4sBDx83eqBk&quot;&gt;Video 2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/BDUAw-IssV0&quot;&gt;Video 3&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/9SYhCrorivs&quot;&gt;Video 4&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/36NWs3MTM60&quot;&gt;Video 5&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/VJ3cs9W83Ug&quot;&gt;Video 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/project/judging/2022/10/01/Innovation-Project-Presentation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/project/judging/2022/10/01/Innovation-Project-Presentation.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
        <category>Judging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to do Research</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How exactly do you do research? The process of doing research is rarely taught in school. Teaching your team the research process, including how to come up with keywords and how to take notes, is very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Start by looking for keywords in the Challenge Guide. What does the challenge say we need to do? Are there any restrictions? What is the overall theme? What words pop out?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Discuss what makes one source more reliable than another. If you have a young team or a team that is not allowed to search online, a coach could generate a list of safe and reliable sources ahead of time and have students select from that subset.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn how to take notes. Taking notes does not mean copying every word down.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn to cite sources. In FLL, citations do not have to follow any particular format. However, it is important to know where your information is coming from. Keeping track of the author and website/links is a great place for a young student to start.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, discuss how to communicate your research to others (each other or judges). For example, some information is best presented in a comparison table. A pie chart might be useful for other information.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information and links for each of these steps, refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flltutorials.com/en/Worksheets.html&quot;&gt;Superpowered Pre-Season Guide for Innovation Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/project/judging/2022/09/01/How-to-do-Research.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/project/judging/2022/09/01/How-to-do-Research.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
        <category>Judging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding Experts</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every season, the topic of “how do I find experts” comes us. The following article takes ideas and discussions shared from the Facebook Group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/FLLShareandLearn/&quot;&gt;FLL: Share &amp;amp; Learn &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Experts” can be very broadly defined. Think outside the box. In the Intro Orbit season, it was very difficult to talk to an astronaut. However, if your team was studying growing plants in space, you could start with a florist or a botanist. Professors at local universities are often a great resource.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This job is not all for the coach. Encourage the students to think about what types of people might work in jobs related to their topic. Encourage the students to draft emails and do the cold calls. It is a great way to develop communication skills. Often times, people will help just because the kids asked.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have a coach look at LinkedIn and see if there are any people working in the field you want.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have a coach join Facebook Groups for a particular field or hobby. For instance if you needed to talk to a truck driver in Cargo Connect, join some truck driver groups and make a post on behalf of you your team.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Think local always. If you need to research delivery trucks, think of the FedEx truck going around your neighborhood. There are people in your local community who are more likely to help local kids.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Search of scientific papers on the topic and then contact the authors.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reach out to your network of friends. Many coaches will make a post on their personal facebook page to ask if anyone knows a particular type of expert.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remember that the expert does not need to live near you. You can always talk to them via Zoom/Google Meets, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/project/judging/2022/08/05/Finding-Experts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/project/judging/2022/08/05/Finding-Experts.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
        <category>Judging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Choosing Between Robots</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your team has designed two different robots. How do we choose between them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Test your robot to see which one is built better. Run the missions ten times. Which robot is more reliable? Keep in mind that reliability is a combination of physical and code attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do specific tests on the robot - 90 degree turns, moving straight, etc. Which one performs better with the same code?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Look at the rubric. There are places where students need to explain the robot code, attachments, and sensor functionality. Which robot would be more interesting to talk about in judging?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Note that you are allowed to take more than one robot to the contest. You can use a different robot in each of the three robot matches. You can take two robots into judging and explain both. One drawback would be having to spend time explaining two robot designs and two strategies in your 5-minute session.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Regardless of what you choose, document the two robots and how you decided which to use when. Share that with judges. Refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flltutorials.com/en/Worksheets.html&quot;&gt;Robot Design Engineering Notebook Worksheets&lt;/a&gt; for sample testing you could do on your robots and how to document the tests.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/project/judging/2022/08/01/Choosing-Between-Robots.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/coachcorner/project/judging/2022/08/01/Choosing-Between-Robots.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoachCorner</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
        <category>Judging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In Common</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity: In Common&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;
Through this activity teams will learn that they have quite a lot in common with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strips of paper (or post-it notes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Poster board to stick them on to with the names of each of the students on the top.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each student is given 6 small pieces/strips of paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Come up with 6 questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each team member should take 6 pieces of paper. On each paper, write the answer to one question: 1) How many siblings do you have? 2) What is your favorite sport? 3) Do you play an instrument (which one)? 4) If you could travel anywhere, where would you go?, 5) What is your favorite subject in school?, 6) Do you have a pet?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Place each paper into a box or hat when you are done.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When everyone is done, pick out one paper at a time and guess who it could be about. Place the post it under the correct name. Find out what you have in common with others on your team.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Core Value Activity was created and shared by Droids Robotics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2021/10/10/In-Common.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2021/10/10/In-Common.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bust the Balloon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity: Bust the Balloon&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;
Through this activity teams will learn the FIRST Core Values, while practicing innovation, persistence, and having fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opaque balloons (if possible), a pen, &amp;amp; 8 small strips of paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Coach needs to write Gracious Professionalism, Coopertition, and each Core Value on small strips of paper.  Then, put one strip of paper into each balloon and blow up &amp;amp; tie the balloons.   If you blow up the balloons a lot, you will make it easier for them to pop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each team member should take a balloon.  One at a time, team members take turns popping the balloons, each using a different method of popping the balloon.  Be creative!  Once the balloon is popped, have each team member find and hold onto the strip of paper.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After all of the balloons have been popped, take turns reading aloud the strips of paper and discuss them as a team.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Notes: This could also be done to learn Robot Game Rules, Missions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Core Value Activity was created and shared by the Shakespearean Pirates on Share &amp;amp; Learn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2021/10/01/Bust-the-Balloon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2021/10/01/Bust-the-Balloon.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chicken Challenge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity: Chicken Challenge&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;
Learn about FLLChicken and learn the importance of giving good instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collect enough parts to build two FLLChickens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/translations/en-us/CoreValues/FLLChickenInstructions.jpg&quot;&gt;FLLChicken Build instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/translations/en-us/CoreValues/FLLChickenHistory.png&quot;&gt;FLLChicken History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setup:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build one complete FLLChicken and leave the rest in pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A divider (trifold or similar) to block the view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions to Team:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decide as a team who will give instructions. This student will have the complete chicken model and will give verbal instructions to the rest of the team to create a duplicate chicken with the loose elements. The student giving instructions may not look at what the rest of the team is doing. The team has 5 minutes to complete their build. Compare your chickens at the end of 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2021/07/08/Chicken-Challenge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2021/07/08/Chicken-Challenge.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trouble</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Building Activity: Trouble: Google Slides Edition&lt;br /&gt;
Author: Arvind from FRC 8027
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Objectives:&lt;/b&gt;
This activity is good for taking a break and playing with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instructions:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a copy of the Trouble &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/14aXQTgzkoKDdboZ3JE1JjIGgBc1SBzynrTAgZW3chds/copy&quot;&gt;google sides&lt;/a&gt; and play in groups of four.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/12/29/Trouble-Google-Slides.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/corevalues/team%20building/2020/12/29/Trouble-Google-Slides.html</guid>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        
        <category>en</category>
        
        <category>CoreValues</category>
        
        <category>Team Building</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
